Guide to the Robert Branner papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Robert Branner Papers,
1936-1973
[Bulk Dates: 1955-1973]
Branner, Robert.
5.5 linear ft. (13 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
6378034
Robert Branner, professor of Art History at Columbia University, was a scholar of French Gothic architecture, sculpture and illuminated manuscripts. Branner’s papers include material related to the art history courses he taught, and to the scholarly research he conducted regarding 13th and 14th century illuminated manuscripts.
Biographical Note
Robert Branner (1927-1973), Columbia University professor of art history, was an expert on French Gothic architecture, sculpture, and illuminated manuscripts. Born and raised in New York, Branner was the son of former vaudeville troupers, Martin Michael Branner and Edith Fabbrini. His father, Mike Branner was also a cartoonist and creator of the comic strip, “Winnie Winkle, the Breadwinner.”
Branner's undergraduate studies at Yale University were interrupted when he was drafted into the United States Army in 1945. He served in Europe and it was there that his interest was piqued in what would become his lifelong work: the study of French Gothic art and architecture. In 1946 Branner returned to civilian life, and to Yale from which he received both his B.A. in Classics in 1948, and his Ph.D. in Art History in 1953. Branner's mentors and colleagues at Yale included Sumner McKnight Crosby, Jean Bony and Louis Grodecki. During his Yale years Branner also studied at the École des Chartres and the Institut d'Art et Archaéologie, and led the excavation work of Bourges Cathedral from 1950-1952. Upon graduation from Yale, Branner married Shirley Prager, a librarian.
Branner began his teaching career at Yale, where he was an instructor from 1952 to 1953, but the bulk of Branner's career, excepting only brief stints at the University of Kansas (1954-1957) and Johns Hopkins University (1969-1971), was spent at Columbia University. Branner taught Art History at Columbia from 1957 until his death in 1973; he became a full professor in 1966 and was the department chair from 1968-1969.
From 1964-1966 Branner served as the director and editor of the Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians. Branner was also a member of the Société Française d'Archéologie and of the Société Nationale des Antiquaires. Over the years Branner's work was funded by Fulbright and Marshall-Allison grants, as well as by the Guggenheim Foundation, the American Council of Learned Societies, the American Philosophical Association and the Council on Research in the Humanities of Columbia University.
Burgundian Gothic Architecture, Branner's first monograph was published in 1960. By 1969 he had authored, Gothic Architecture, La Cathedrale de Bourges et sa Place dans l'Architecture Gothique, Chartres Cathedral and his most renowned work, St. Louis and the Court Style in Gothic Architecture. Although Branner's initial academic interest was the study of Gothic architecture, he spent his final years studying 13th and 14th century illuminated manuscripts. Manuscript Paintings in Paris during the Reign of Saint Louis; a Study of Styles, published posthumously, was the culmination of that research.
Shirley Prager Branner's “A Bibliography and Index to the Works of Robert Branner.” Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians, 34, no. 3 (October 1975): 167-172 provides a comprehensive list of Branner's work. In 1973 Robert Branner died from complications following heart surgery.
Scope and Content
The Robert Branner Papers include material related to the art history courses Branner taught, and to the scholarly research he conducted regarding 13th and 14th century illuminated manuscripts.
The teaching material includes bibliographies, chronologies, slide lists, lecture notes, syllabi, class lists, notes, sketches, and student papers. Also included are notes Branner took during classes or lectures he attended, and from papers that he read. Scholars represented in his notes include Jurgis Baltrušaitis, Jean Bony, Sumner Crosby, Henri Focillon, Louis Grodecki, Julius Held, George Kubler and Charles Seymour Jr.
The scholarly-research material Branner accumulated based on his study of 13th and 14th century manuscripts includes notes, correspondence, and photocopies or photographs of pages from manuscripts. Many of the folders also contain annotations written by his wife, Shirley Branner.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series.
Series I: Teaching Materials, 1936-1973
Subseries I.1. Columbia University, 1957-1973
Subseries I.2. University of Kansas, 1955-1957
Subseries I.3. Other Universities, 1960s
Subseries I.4. Notes and Materials -- Other Scholars
Series II. Medieval Manuscript Research Materials, 1965-1973.
Subjects
Columbia University.--Dept. of Art History and Archaeology.; Columbia University--Faculty.; Columbia University.--Faculty of Fine Arts.; Branner, Robert.; Branner, Shirley Prager.; Art--History.; Illumination of books and manuscripts, Gothic.
Access Restrictions
Three folders (Box 1, folders 13 and 18, and box 2, folder 1) which contain graded, student papers, are restricted. The folders in Box 1 are restricted until 2039; the folder in Box 2 is restricted until 2049. The remainder of the collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Prager Branner Gift, 1995.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Teaching Materials, 1936-1973
  This series contains correspondence, bibliographies, chronologies, slide lists, lecture notes, syllabi, class lists, notes, sketches, and student papers. Also included are notes that Branner took during classes or lectures he attended, and from the papers that he read. Material in this series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries I.1. Columbia University, 1957-1973
    This subseries comprises correspondence, bibliographies, chronologies, slide lists, lecture notes, syllabi, class lists, notes, sketches, and student papers.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Courses Taught, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fine Arts -- Course Instructions, 1957, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fine Arts -- Humanities B, 1959-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fine Arts -- Humanities C 1121, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fine Arts 53, 1958-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fine Arts 54, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fine Arts 153 -- Gothic Architecture, 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fine Arts 154, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fine Arts 156 -- The Gothic World, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fine Arts 157A -- Gothic Sculpture, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fine Arts 157B -- Paris Through the Ages, 1960-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fine Arts 157B -- Paris Through the Ages -- Student Paper, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      [restricted until 2039]
    - Fine Arts 206 -- Museum Studies, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fine Arts 255-256, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fine Arts 257 -- Pre-classical Style -- Seminar, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fine Arts 258 -- The Cathedral of Chartres and its Succession, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Fine Arts 258 -- Student Paper, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Fine Arts 259, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - G 6002 -- The Literature of Art, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - G 6010 Y -- Art History Colloquium -- Student Paper, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [restricted until 2049]
    - Gothic Art, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Gothic Art, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Gothic Art -- S4353 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gothic Art -- 12th Century, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gothic Art -- 12th Century, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Gothic Art -- 13th Century -- Lecture Course, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Gothic Art -- 13th Century -- Seminar, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gothic Art -- 13th Century -- Seminar report -- "The Problem of the Stemma in the Bible Moralisée, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gothic Art in France -- Reims Cathedral, 1960s-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Medieval Colloquium, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Romanesque Architecture, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Romanesque Architecture -- Spring Colloquium, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Subseries I.2. University of Kansas, 1955-1957
    Making up this subseries are bibliographies, chronologies, slide lists, lecture notes, syllabi, class lists, notes, sketches, and student papers from the art history courses.
    - American Civilization, 1955-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Gothic World, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Great Artists, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - History of Art -- 71, 1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - History of Art -- 72, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - History of Art -- The Baroque, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - History of Art -- Sculpture, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Medieval Art, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Medieval Painting, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Renaissance Painting, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.3. Other Universities, 1960s
    Contained in this subseries are bibliographies, chronologies, slide lists, lecture notes, syllabi, class lists, notes, sketches, and student papers from the art history courses Branner taught at Yale University and at Johns Hopkins University.
    - Johns Hopkins University -- Introductory Course, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Yale University -- Four Cathedrals, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.4. Notes and Materials -- Other Scholars, 1936-1961
    This subseries includes Branner’s notes and materials based on the work of Jurgis Baltrušaitis, Jean Bony, Sumner Crosby, Henri Focillon, Louis Grodecki, Julius Held, George Kubler and Charles Seymour Jr.
    - Baltrušaitis, Jurgis, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Bony, Jean -- English and Gothic Architecture, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Crosby, Sumner, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Focillon, Henri --"The Great Experiences: The 11th Century"--Translation, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Focillon, Henri -- Lectures --Transcripts, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Grodecki, Louis -- Thesis Notes, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Held, Julius -- Rubens' Drawings, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Kubler, George -- History of Art and Cultural Anthropology, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Seymour, Charles, Jr. -- Renaissance, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series II: Medieval Manuscript Research Materials, 1965-1973, undated
  This series comprises scholarly-research material Branner accumulated based on his study of 13th and 14th century illuminated manuscripts. Included are notes, correspondence, and photocopies or photographs of pages from manuscripts. Many of the folders also contain annotations written by his wife, Shirley Prager Branner. These materials are arranged alphabetically by city, and within cities, alphabetically by repository.
  - Admont, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Amiens, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Antwerp, 1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arras -- Bibliothèque Municpale -- 31-38, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Arras -- Bibliothèque Municpale -- 49-991, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Arras -- Bibliothèque Municpale - 530, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Assisi, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Auxerre, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Avranches, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Baltimore -- Walters Art Gallery -- Bible, 1965, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Baltimore -- Walters Art Gallery -- Breviary, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Baltimore -- Walters Art Gallery -- Psalter, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bamberg, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Bari -- San Nicola, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Basel, 1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Berlin, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bern, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Besançon, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bethesda, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Boston, 1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Boulogne, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Breslau, 1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bruges, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brussels, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Budapest, 1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cambrai, 1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cambridge -- Fitzwilliam Museum, 1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cambridge -- Fitzwilliam Museum -- Isabella Psalter, 1965-1972, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cambridge -- Trinity College, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1966-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Camden, Maine -- Eric Sexton College, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Carpentras, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Chalons sur Marne, 1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Chantilly, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Charlottesville, Virginia, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chartres, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Chicago, Art Institute of, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Cividale, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cologne, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Colorado Springs, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Copenhagen -- General, 1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Copenhagen -- Christina Psalter, 1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Copenhagen -- Thott Psalter, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Crakow, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dijon, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Donaueschingen, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Douai -- 17, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Douai -- 18, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Douai -- 21, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Douai -- 22, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Douai -- 156, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Douai -- 173, 340, 592, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Dublin, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Durham, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Edinburgh, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Erlangen, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Eton, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Florence, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Florence -- Plutarch, 1970-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Frankfurt, 1967-1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Giessen, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Göttweig, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hague, 1970-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hastings-on-Hudson -- Kapp Bible, 1972-1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Hatfield House, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Holkham Hall, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kansas City -- Nelson Gallery, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Klagenfurt, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Laon, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Le Mans, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Leyden, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Liege, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Lille, 1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Leningrad, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - London -- Abbey, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - London -- British Museum -- General, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 11698 1972, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 15253 undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 15452 undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 16410 undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 17341 undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 17742 undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 17868 undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 21114 undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 21926 undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 22399 undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 23935 undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 24678 and 24683 undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 26655 undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 27694 undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 28681 undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 28784 undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 30045 undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 35085 undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 381145 1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 38116 undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 47674 undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - London -- British Museum -- Add. 54235 1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - London -- British Museum -- Arundel, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - London -- British Museum -- Egerton 1151, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - London -- British Museum -- Egerton 2652, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - London -- British Museum -- Harley 1297, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - London -- British Museum -- Harley 2839, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - London -- British Museum -- Lausdonne, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal I. B. xii, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal I. C. i., undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal I. C. ii, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal I. D. i., undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal I. D. x, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal 2. B. ii, 1968, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal 3. E. i.-viii, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal 4. E. vi, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal 4. E. vii, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - London -- British Museum -- Royal 20 D. vi, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - London -- British Museum -- Stowe 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - London -- British Museum -- Yates -- Thompson 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - London -- British Museum -- Yates -- Thompson 9, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - London -- British Museum -- Yates -- Thompson 12, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - London -- British Museum -- Yates -- Thompson 18, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - London -- British Museum -- Yates -- Thompson 22, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - London -- Davis Collection, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - London -- Ehrmann, Lambeth and Soane, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - London -- Westminster Abbey, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Luxembourg, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Lyon, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Madrid -- Biblioteca Nacional, 1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Madrid -- Mus. Lazaro Galdiano, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Manchester -- John Rylands Library -- 16, 1968-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Manchester -- John Rylands Library -- 22, 1968-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Melbourne, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Metz, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Milan -- Biblioteca Ambrosiana -- E23, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Milan -- Biblioteca Ambrosiana -- Q34, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Montpellier, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Munich, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Nantes, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Naples, 1966-1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - New Haven -- Yale -- Beinecke, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - New Haven -- Yale -- Law Library, 1966-1970, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - New York -- Ewing Collection, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - New York -- General Theological Seminary, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York -- Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- Glazier, 1970-1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M -- General, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 65-M269, 1966-1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 283, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 313, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 440, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M638, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 644, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - New York -- Pierpont Morgan Library -- M 729-M 851, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - New York -- Public Library, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - New York -- Union Theological Seminary, 1970-1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Nüremberg, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Orléans, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Oxford -- Balliol College, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Add. A 46, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Bodley 270b, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Canon Bibl. Lat. 15, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Canon Bibl. Lat. 41, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Canon Bibl. Lat. 47, 1970, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Canon Bibl. Lat. 52, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- D'Orville 212, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Douce 48, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Douce 50, 1965-1967, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Douce113 and 381, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- E. D. Clarke 31, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Laud Latin, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Oxford -- Bodleian Library -- Rawlinson G. 6, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Oxford -- Brasenose College, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Oxford -- Christ Church, 1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Oxford -- Wadham College, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Padua, 1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Palermo, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Paris -- General --Early, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Paris -- Archives Nationales, 1966, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 25, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 108, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 149, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 589-945, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 1170, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 1186, 1973-1974, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Paris -- Arsenal -- 3516, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 9, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 12, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 15 and 19, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 36 and 38, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 71, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 131-144, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 414, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Paris -- Mazarine -- 422 and 426, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 241, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 412, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 493, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 495, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 696, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 899, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 963, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 1610, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 1633, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 2163, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 2186, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 5594, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 6447, 1970, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 9081, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 9574, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 12576 undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 12581 undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 13502 undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Paris -- Nationale -- Fr. 20118 undated (Box 9, Folder 38)